<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="https://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Noord]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/</link><image><url>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/favicon.png</url><title>Noord - Multipurpose Ghost Blog Theme</title><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/</link></image><generator>Ghost 3.19</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:31:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to Ghost]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome, it's great to have you here.
We know that first impressions are important, so we've populated your new site with some initial getting started posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/welcome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad064c</guid><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Pollock]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome, it's great to have you here.</p><p>We know that first impressions are important, so we've populated your new site with some initial <strong>getting started</strong> posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!</p><p><strong>A few things you should know upfront</strong>:</p><ol><li>Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That's who it works best for. </li><li>The entire platform can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It's very powerful, but does require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog. </li><li>For the best experience we recommend downloading the <a href="https://ghost.org/downloads/">Ghost Desktop App</a> for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device. </li></ol><p>Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our <a href="https://ghost.org/pricing">Ghost(Pro)</a> service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern publishing.</p><p>The version of Ghost you are looking at right now would not have been made possible without generous contributions from the open source <a href="https://github.com/TryGhost">community</a>.</p><h2 id="next-up-the-editor">Next up, the editor</h2><p>The main thing you'll want to read about next is probably: <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/the-editor/">the Ghost editor</a>. This is where the good stuff happens.</p><blockquote><em>By the way, once you're done reading, you can simply delete the default <strong>Ghost</strong> user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts! </em></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing posts with Ghost]]></title><description><![CDATA[Getting started with the editor is simple, with familiar formatting options in a functional toolbar and the ability to add dynamic content seamlessly]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/the-editor/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad064b</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsty Bowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1539035104074-dee66086b5e3.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1539035104074-dee66086b5e3.jpg" alt="Writing posts with Ghost"><p>Ghost has a powerful visual editor with familiar formatting options, as well as the ability to seamlessly add dynamic content. </p><p>Select the text to add formatting, headers or create links, or use Markdown shortcuts to do the work for you - if that's your thing. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://static.ghost.org/v2.0.0/images/formatting-editor-demo.gif" class="kg-image" alt="Writing posts with Ghost"></figure><h2 id="rich-editing-at-your-fingertips">Rich editing at your fingertips</h2><p>The editor can also handle rich media objects, called <strong>cards</strong>. </p><p>You can insert a card either by clicking the  <code>+</code>  button on a new line, or typing  <code>/</code>  on a new line to search for a particular card. This allows you to efficiently insert<strong> images</strong>, <strong>markdown</strong>, <strong>html</strong> and <strong>embeds</strong>.</p><p><strong>For Example</strong>:</p><ul><li>Insert a video from YouTube directly into your content by pasting the URL </li><li>Create unique content like a button or content opt-in using the HTML card</li><li>Need to share some code? Embed code blocks directly </li></ul><pre><code>&lt;header class="site-header outer"&gt;
    &lt;div class="inner"&gt;
        {{&gt; "site-nav"}}
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;</code></pre><h1 id="working-with-images-in-posts">Working with images in posts</h1><p>You can add images to your posts in many ways:</p><ul><li>Upload from your computer</li><li>Click and drag an image into the browser</li><li>Paste directly into the editor from your clipboard</li><li>Insert using a URL</li></ul><p>Once inserted you can blend images beautifully into your content at different sizes and add captions wherever needed.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1540101206055-7cc7bd8522c6.jpg" width="600" height="900" alt="Writing posts with Ghost"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1540298287461-5e2125e7e423.jpg" width="600" height="900" alt="Writing posts with Ghost"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1539136831565-c85f368448a3.jpg" width="600" height="900" alt="Writing posts with Ghost"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@trapnation">Andre Benz</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><p>The post settings menu and publishing options can be found in the top right hand corner. For more advanced tips on post settings check out the <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/publishing-options/">publishing options</a> post!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Publishing options]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Ghost editor has everything you need to fully optimise your content. This is where you can add tags and authors, feature a post, or turn a post into a page]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/publishing-options/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad064a</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhi Leedam]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1529698719798-147db6e24a84.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1529698719798-147db6e24a84.jpg" alt="Publishing options"><p>The Ghost editor has everything you need to fully optimise your content. This is where you can add tags and authors, feature a post, or turn a post into a page. </p><blockquote>Access the post settings menu in the top right hand corner of the editor. </blockquote><h2 id="post-feature-image">Post feature image</h2><p>Insert your post feature image from the very top of the post settings menu. Consider resizing or optimising your image first to ensure it's an appropriate size.</p><h2 id="structured-data-seo">Structured data &amp; SEO</h2><p>Customise your social media sharing cards for Facebook and Twitter, enabling you to add custom images, titles and descriptions for social media.</p><p>There’s no need to hard code your meta data. You can set your meta title and description using the post settings tool, which has a handy character guide and SERP preview. </p><p>Ghost will automatically implement structured data for your publication using JSON-LD to further optimise your content.</p><pre><code>{
    "@context": "https://schema.org",
    "@type": "Article",
    "publisher": {
        "@type": "Organization",
        "name": "Publishing options",
        "logo": "https://static.ghost.org/ghost-logo.svg"
    },
    "author": {
        "@type": "Person",
        "name": "Ghost",
        "url": "https://demo.ghost.io/author/ghost/",
        "sameAs": []
    },
    "headline": "Publishing options",
    "url": "https://demo.ghost.io/publishing-options",
    "datePublished": "2018-08-08T11:44:00.000Z",
    "dateModified": "2018-08-09T12:06:21.000Z",
    "keywords": "Getting Started",
    "description": "The Ghost editor has everything you need to fully optimise your content. This is where you can add tags and authors, feature a post, or turn a post into a page.",
    }
}</code></pre><p>You can test that the structured data <a href="https://schema.org/">schema</a> on your site is working as it should using <a href="https://search.google.com/structured-data/testing-tool" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Google’s structured data tool</a>. </p><h2 id="code-injection">Code Injection</h2><p>This tool allows you to inject code on a per post or page basis, or across your entire site. This means you can modify CSS, add unique tracking codes, or add other scripts to the head or foot of your publication without making edits to your theme files. </p><p><strong>To add code site-wide</strong>, use the code injection tool <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/build-a-beautiful-website/">in the main admin menu</a>. This is useful for adding a Facebook Pixel, a Google Analytics tracking code, or to start tracking with any other analytics tool.</p><p><strong>To add code to a post or page</strong>, use the code injection tool within the post settings menu. This is useful if you want to add art direction, scripts or styles that are only applicable to one post or page. </p><p>From here, you might be interested in managing some more specific <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/admin-settings/">admin settings</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Managing admin settings]]></title><description><![CDATA[There are a couple of things to do next while you're getting set up: making your site private and inviting your team]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/admin-settings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0649</guid><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsty Bowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1508504874959-d752ef44e99a.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1508504874959-d752ef44e99a.jpg" alt="Managing admin settings"><p>There are a couple of things to do next while you're getting set up:</p><h1 id="make-your-site-private">Make your site private</h1><p>If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a basic shared pass-phrase.</p><p>You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/build-a-beautiful-website/">General Settings</a>:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://static.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png" class="kg-image" alt="Managing admin settings"></figure><p>Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep your site under the radar.</p><p>Do remember though, this is <em>not</em> secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for some very basic privacy.</p><hr><h1 id="invite-your-team">Invite your team </h1><p>Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team:</p><p><strong>Contributors</strong><br>This is the base user level in Ghost. Contributors can create and edit their own draft posts, but they are unable to edit drafts of others or publish posts. Contributors are <strong>untrusted</strong> users with the most basic access to your publication.</p><p><strong>Authors</strong><br>Authors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Authors can write, edit  and publish their own posts. Authors are <strong>trusted</strong> users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, they should be set as Contributors.</p><p><strong>Editors</strong><br>Editors are the 3rd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new Contributors+Authors to the site.</p><p><strong>Administrators</strong><br>The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.<br><br><strong>The Owner</strong><br>There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable. For example: billing details, if using <a href="https://ghost.org/pricing/"><strong>Ghost(Pro)</strong></a>.</p><blockquote><em>It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</em></blockquote><p>Next up: <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/organising-content/">Organising your content</a> </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Organising your content]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ghost has a flexible organisational taxonomy called tags which can be used to configure your site structure using dynamic routing]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/organising-content/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0648</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Dorney]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1565736736474-5decadc950b3.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1565736736474-5decadc950b3.jpg" alt="Organising your content"><p>Ghost has a flexible organisational taxonomy called<strong> tags</strong> which can be used to configure your site structure using <strong>dynamic routing</strong>. </p><h1 id="basic-tagging">Basic Tagging</h1><p>You can think of tags like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.</p><p>When you create content for your publication you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. </p><p>For example you may tag some content with  News and other content with Podcast, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on <code>/tag/news/</code> and <code>/tag/weather/</code>, respectively.</p><p>If you tag a post with both <code>News</code> <em>and</em> <code>Weather</code> - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.</p><h1 id="the-primary-tag">The primary tag</h1><p>Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. </p><h3 id="news-technology-startup">News, Technology, Startup</h3><p>So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add related tags which are less important.</p><h1 id="private-tags">Private tags</h1><p>Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.</p><p>For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.</p><h3 id="news-video">News, #video</h3><p>Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting. </p><blockquote>You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive <a href="https://ghost.org/docs/api/handlebars-themes/">theme documentation</a>.</blockquote><h1 id="dynamic-routing">Dynamic Routing</h1><p>Dynamic routing gives you the ultimate freedom to build a custom publication to suit your needs. Routes are rules that map URL patterns to your content and templates. </p><p>For example, you may not want content tagged with <code>News</code> to exist on: <code>example.com/tag/news</code>. Instead, you want it to exist on <code>example.com/news</code> . </p><p>In this case you can use dynamic routes to create customised collections of content on your site. It's also possible to use multiple templates in your theme to render each content type differently.</p><p>There are lots of use cases for dynamic routing with Ghost, here are a few common examples: </p><ul><li>Setting a custom home page with its own template</li><li>Having separate content hubs for blog and podcast, that render differently, and have custom RSS feeds to support two types of content</li><li>Creating a founders column as a unique view, by filtering content created by specific authors</li><li>Including dates in permalinks for your posts</li><li>Setting posts to have a URL relative to their primary tag like <code>example.com/europe/story-title/</code><br></li></ul><blockquote><em>Dynamic routing can be configured in Ghost using <a href="https://yaml.org/spec/1.2/spec.html" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">YAML</a> files. Read our dynamic routing <a href="https://ghost.org/docs/api/handlebars-themes/routing/">documentation</a> for further details.</em></blockquote><p>You can further customise your site using <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/apps-integrations/">Apps &amp; Integrations</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apps & integrations]]></title><description><![CDATA[There are three primary ways to work with third-party services in Ghost: using Zapier, editing your theme, or]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/apps-integrations/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0647</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Dorney]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1500514692669-6ad57dec39e0.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1500514692669-6ad57dec39e0.jpg" alt="Apps & integrations"><p>There are three primary ways to work with third-party services in Ghost: using Zapier, editing your theme, or using the Ghost API.</p><h1 id="zapier">Zapier</h1><p>You can connect your Ghost site to over 1,000 external services using the official integration with <a href="https://zapier.com">Zapier</a>.</p><p>Zapier sets up automations with Triggers and Actions, which allows you to create and customise a wide range of connected applications.</p><blockquote><strong>Example</strong>: When someone new subscribes to a newsletter on a Ghost site (Trigger) then the contact information is automatically pushed into MailChimp (Action).</blockquote><p><strong>Here are the most popular Ghost-Zapier automation templates:</strong> </p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><script src="https://zapier.com/apps/embed/widget.js?services=Ghost&container=true&limit=8"></script>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h1 id="editing-your-theme">Editing your theme</h1><p>One of the biggest advantages of using Ghost over centralised platforms is that you have total control over the front end of your site. Either customise your existing theme, or create a new theme from scratch with our <a href="https://ghost.org/docs/api/handlebars-themes/">Theme SDK</a>. </p><p>You can integrate <em>any</em> front end code into a Ghost theme without restriction, and it will work just fine. No restrictions!</p><p><strong>Here are some common examples</strong>:</p><ul><li>Include comments on a Ghost blog with <a href="https://ghost.org/integrations/disqus/">Disqus</a> or <a href="https://ghost.org/integrations/discourse/">Discourse</a></li><li>Implement <a href="https://ghost.org/integrations/">MathJAX</a> with a little bit of JavaScript</li><li>Add syntax highlighting to your code snippets using <a href="https://prismjs.com/">Prism.js</a></li><li>Integrate any dynamic forms from <a href="https://www.google.com/forms/">Google</a> or <a href="https://www.typeform.com/">Typeform</a> to capture data</li><li>Just about anything which uses JavaScript, APIs and Markup.</li></ul><h1 id="using-the-public-api">Using the Public API</h1><p>Ghost itself is driven by a set of core APIs, and so you can access the Public Ghost JSON API from external webpages or applications in order to pull data and display it in other places.</p><blockquote>The Ghost API is <a href="https://ghost.org/docs/api/">thoroughly documented</a> and straightforward to work with for developers of almost any level. </blockquote><p>Alright, the last post in our welcome-series! If you're curious about creating your own Ghost theme from scratch, here are <a href="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/build-a-beautiful-website/">some more details</a> on how that works.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a beautiful website]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ghost comes with a beautiful theme called Noord, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for any creative purposes]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/build-a-beautiful-website/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0646</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsty Bowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1477696957384-3b1d731c4cff-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1477696957384-3b1d731c4cff-1.jpg" alt="Build a beautiful website"><p>Ghost comes with a beautiful theme called <strong>Noord</strong>, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for any creative purposes. It featured Ajax page transitions and subscription form, while providing sleek fuzzy-search functionality and many more custom features.</p><p>Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a set of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. For example: <code>{{author.name}}</code> outputs the name of the current author.</p><p>The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at <a href="https://github.com/TryGhost/Casper">the source code for Casper</a>, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together.</p><ul><li><code>default.hbs</code> is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template.</li><li><code>post.hbs</code> is the file used in the context of viewing a post.</li><li><code>index.hbs</code> is the file used in the context of viewing the home page.</li><li>and so on</li></ul><p>We've got <a href="https://ghost.org/docs/api/handlebars-themes/">full and extensive theme documentation</a> which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use.</p><p>If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a <strong>themes</strong> section on our <a href="https://forum.ghost.org/c/themes">public Ghost forum</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Playing with fire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fire is the rapid oxidation of a material in the exothermic chemical process of combustion, releasing heat, light, and various reaction products]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/playing-with-fire/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0654</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhi Leedam]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1518351330216-a38c8ab14640.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1518351330216-a38c8ab14640.jpg" alt="Playing with fire"><p><strong>Fire</strong> is the rapid oxidation of a material in the exothermic chemical process of combustion, releasing heat, light, and various reaction products.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup> Slower oxidative processes like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rusting">rusting</a> or digestion are not included by this definition.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There may be a great fire in our hearts, yet no one ever comes to warm himself at it, and the passers-by see only a wisp of smoke.<br>
<cite>Vincent Van Gogh</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fire is hot because the conversion of the weak double bond in molecular oxygen, O<sub>2</sub>, to the stronger bonds in the combustion products carbon dioxide and water releases energy (418 kJ per 32 g of O<sub>2</sub>); the bond energies of the fuel play only a minor role here.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup> At a certain point in the combustion reaction, called the ignition point, flames are produced. The flame is the visible portion of the fire. Flames consist primarily of carbon dioxide, water vapor, oxygen and nitrogen. If hot enough, the gases may become ionized to produce <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plasma_(physics)">plasma</a>.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">[3]</a></sup> Depending on the substances alight, and any impurities outside, the color of the flame and the fire's intensity will be different.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Content categories</th>
<th>Flow content</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Permitted content</td>
<td>An optional <code>&lt;caption&gt;</code> element; <br>zero or more <code>&lt;colgroup&gt;</code> elements; <br>an optional <code>&lt;thead&gt;</code> element; <br>an optional <code>&lt;tfoot&gt;</code> element;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tag omission</td>
<td>None, both the start tag and the end tag are mandatory</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Permitted parent elements</td>
<td>Any element that accepts flow content</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Normative document</td>
<td><a href="https://www.whatwg.org/specs/web-apps/current-work/multipage/tabular-data.html#the-table-element" target="_blank">HTML5, section 4.9.1</a> (<a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/struct/tables.html#edef-TABLE" target="_blank">HTML4.01, section 11.2.1</a>)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Fire in its most common form can result in conflagration, which has the potential to cause physical damage through burning. Fire is an important process that affects ecological systems around the globe. The positive effects of fire include stimulating growth and maintaining various ecological systems.</p>
<hr class="footnotes-sep">
<section class="footnotes">
<ol class="footnotes-list">
<li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p>&quot;Glossary of Wildland Fire Terminology&quot;. National Wildfire Coordinating Group. November 2009. <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn2" class="footnote-item"><p>Schmidt-Rohr, K (2015). &quot;Why Combustions Are Always Exothermic, Yielding About 418 kJ per Mole of O2&quot;. J. Chem. Educ. 92 (12): 2094–99. <a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn3" class="footnote-item"><p>Helmenstine, Anne Marie. &quot;What is the State of Matter of Fire or Flame? Is it a Liquid, Solid, or Gas?&quot; <a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wild mountain adventures]]></title><description><![CDATA[A romantic journey is the best way to fill your relationship with a loved one with new feelings and vivid emotions. This journey will leave only pleasant impressions and will be the beginning of a new stage of your life]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/wild-mountain-adventures/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0651</guid><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsty Bowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1566206199489-f6604b30c0b1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1566206199489-f6604b30c0b1.jpg" alt="Wild mountain adventures"><p>A romantic journey is the best way to fill your relationship with a loved one with new feelings and vivid emotions. This journey will leave only pleasant impressions and will be the beginning of a new stage of your life.</p><p>Many couples in love choose Spain as a place for solemn registration of marriage or a honeymoon. This country attracts attention with its hot sun and beautiful beaches. Spain is known for its small cozy towns, endless coastline, palm trees, orange gardens, and fascinating history of the state itself. The city of Madrid, which is the capital of Spain, is an ideal place for the best honeymoon.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><blockquote>
<p>May your trails be crooked, winding, lonesome, dangerous, leading to the most amazing view. May your mountains rise into and above the clouds.<br>
<cite>Edward Abbey</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Spain is also a country of contrasts. Noisy Ibiza will be great for lovers of outdoor activities and sleepless nights; Port de Pollen?a will become a paradise for those who want to relax and to spend romsantic evenings together. Barcelona is famous for its sights. The city has a huge number of comfortable hotels with rooms for lovebirds and newlyweds. Spain is one of the oldest countries in Europe. So, it always has something to tell you!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562151404-9f198236130d.jpg" width="1290" height="764" alt="Wild mountain adventures"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1563226659-69d3d7239a21.jpg" width="1290" height="764" alt="Wild mountain adventures"></div></div><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562361233-cc2d6fcd95f5.jpg" width="1290" height="1177" alt="Wild mountain adventures"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562361233-2c977823327f.jpg" width="1290" height="771" alt="Wild mountain adventures"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@vadimsadovski">Vadim Sadovski</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><h2 id="weekend-in-a-mountain-valley">Weekend In A Mountain Valley</h2><p>Italy is a favorite holiday destination for lovers. After all, it is the birthplace of Romeo and Juliet. It was in this country, in Verona, that the loving-tragic events of the famous play took place. Everyone can visit the courtyard at Juliet`s house and even watch a theatrical performance. Every year in Verona, on the eve of St. Valentine`s Day, the festival Verona In Love is held. These events are certainly connected with the tragedy of Shakespeare. Part of the city is decorated with illumination in the form of large and small hearts. There are performances, food and wine tastings, and fairs on the streets.</p><blockquote>Instead of trying to make your life perfect, give yourself the freedom to make it an adventure, and go ever upward.</blockquote><p>If you prefer to know the country from within, then you have to visit Rome. It is famous for its history and many museums, attractions and delicious cuisine. The castle, which is located in the vicinity of Rome, is another popular place for lovers. In this place a lot of marriages are concluded.</p><p>Italy is famous for its wines. Therefore, wine connoisseurs simply have to visit the Chianti Valley. Here you can not only taste wine, but also get a wine therapy. In Venice, you will gain an indescribable experience while going on a gondola. Italy is a country of real, bold relationships and feelings!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Merry go round of life]]></title><description><![CDATA[The search for life's meaning has produced much philosophical, scientific, theological, and metaphysical speculation throughout history. Different people and cultures]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/merry-go-round-of-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0653</guid><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Dorney]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1502136969935-8d8eef54d77b.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1502136969935-8d8eef54d77b.jpg" alt="Merry go round of life"><p>The search for life's meaning has produced much philosophical, scientific, theological, and metaphysical speculation throughout history. Different people and cultures believe different things for the answer to this question.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><blockquote>
<p>I don't believe people are looking for the meaning of life as much as they are looking for the experience of being alive.<br>
<cite>Joseph Campbell</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>The meaning of life as we perceive it is derived from philosophical and religious contemplation of, and scientific inquiries about existence, social ties, consciousness, and happiness. Many other issues are also involved, such as symbolic meaning, ontology, value, purpose, ethics, good and evil, free will, the existence of one or multiple gods, conceptions of God, the soul, and the afterlife.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1527786356703-4b100091cd2c.jpg" width="1290" height="968" alt="Merry go round of life"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1561646674-fdcbc81c3a76.jpg" width="680" height="907" alt="Merry go round of life"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@seemoris">Caleb George</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><p>Scientific contributions focus primarily on describing related empirical facts about the universe, exploring the context and parameters concerning the "how" of life. Science also studies and can provide recommendations for the pursuit of well-being and a related <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_of_morality">conception of morality</a>. An alternative, humanistic approach poses the question, "What is the meaning of <em>my</em> life?"</p><h2 id="nature-of-meaning-in-life">Nature of meaning in life</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>The most common definitions of meaning in life involve three components. First, Reker and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_T._P._Wong" target="_blank">Wong</a> define personal meaning as the &quot;cognizance of order, coherence and purpose in one's existence, the pursuit and attainment of worthwhile goals, and an accompanying sense of fulfillment&quot; (p. 221).<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each man must look to himself to teach him the meaning of life. It is not something discovered: it is something molded.<br>
<cite>Antoine de Saint-Exupery</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In 2016 Martela and Steger defined meaning as coherence, purpose, and significance.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup> In contrast, Wong has proposed a four-component solution to the question of meaning in life,<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">[3]</a></sup><sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4">[4]</a></sup> with the four components purpose, understanding, responsibility, and enjoyment (PURE):</p>
<ol>
<li>You need to choose a worthy <strong>purpose</strong> or a significant life goal.</li>
<li>You need to have sufficient <strong>understanding</strong> of who you are, what life demands of you, and how you can play a significant role in life.</li>
<li>You and you alone are <strong>responsible</strong> for deciding what kind of life you want to live, and what constitutes a significant and worthwhile life goal.</li>
<li>You will <strong>enjoy</strong> a deep sense of significance and satisfaction only when you have exercised your responsibility for self-determination and actively pursue a worthy life-goal.</li>
</ol>
<p>Thus, a sense of significance permeates every dimension of meaning, rather than stands as a separate factor.</p>
<p>Although most psychology researchers consider meaning in life as a subjective feeling or judgment, most philosophers propose that there are also objective, concrete criteria for what constitutes meaning in life. Wong has proposed that whether life is meaningful depends not only on subjective feelings but, more importantly, on whether a person's goal-striving and life as a whole is meaningful according to some objective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normative_ethics" target="_blank">normative standard</a>.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4:1">[4:1]</a></sup></p>
<hr class="footnotes-sep">
<section class="footnotes">
<ol class="footnotes-list">
<li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p>Reker, G.T., &amp; Wong, P.T.P. (1988). Aging as an individual process: Towards a theory of personal meaning. In J.E. Birren, &amp; V.L. Bengston (Eds.), Emergent theories of aging (pp. 214-246). New York: Springer. <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn2" class="footnote-item"><p>Martela, F., &amp; Steger, M.F. (2016). The three meanings of meaning in life: Distinguishing coherence, purpose, and significance. The Journal of Positive Psychology, 11(5), 531-545. <a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn3" class="footnote-item"><p>Wong, P.T.P. (2011). Towards a balanced interactive model of the good life. Canadian Psychology, 52(2), 69-81. <a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn4" class="footnote-item"><p>Wong, P.T.P. (2012). From logotherapy to meaning-centered counseling and therapy. In P.T.P. Wong (Ed.), The human quest for meaning: Theories, research, and applications (2nd ed., pp. 619-647). <a href="#fnref4" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a> <a href="#fnref4:1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The ride of a lifetime]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is a series of spiritual, or supernatural beliefs regarding fortune. These beliefs vary widely from one to another, but most agree that luck can be influenced through]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/the-ride-of-a-lifetime/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0658</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhi Leedam]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1510479524860-95998e54a8c6.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1510479524860-95998e54a8c6.jpg" alt="The ride of a lifetime"><p>There is a series of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spiritualism">spiritual</a>, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supernatural">supernatural</a> beliefs regarding fortune. These beliefs vary widely from one to another, but most agree that luck can be influenced through spiritual means by performing certain rituals or by avoiding certain circumstances.</p><p>Abrahamic religions believe God controls future events; belief in luck or fate is criticised in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Isaiah">Book of Isaiah</a>chapter 65, verses 11-12:</p><blockquote>What will happen to you for offering food and wine to the gods you call <em>good luck</em> and <em>fate</em>? Your luck will end.</blockquote><p>Luck can also be a belief in an organization of fortunate and unfortunate events. Luck is a form of superstitionwhich is interpreted differently by different individuals. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Jung">Carl Jung</a> coined the term synchronicity, which he described as "a meaningful coincidence".</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1525226637460-98683232b412.jpg" width="680" height="907" alt="The ride of a lifetime"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1500514966906-fe245eea9344.jpg" width="1290" height="967" alt="The ride of a lifetime"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jadav">Jakub David</a> and <a href="https://unsplash.com/@seemoris">Caleb George</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><p>Belief in the extent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divine_Providence">Divine Providence</a> varies; most acknowledge providence as at least a partial, if not complete influence on luck. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christianity">Christianity</a>, in its early development, accommodated many traditional practices which at different times, accepted omens and practiced forms of ritual sacrifice in order to divine the will of their supreme being or to influence divine favoritism. The concepts of <strong>"Divine Grace"</strong> or <strong>"Blessing"</strong> as they are described by believers closely resemble what is referred to as "luck" by others.</p><h2 id="as-a-self-fulfilling-prophecy">As a self-fulfilling prophecy</h2><p>Some evidence supports the idea that belief in luck acts like a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Placebo">placebo</a>, producing positive thinking and improving people's responses to events.</p><p>In personality psychology, people reliably differ from each other depending on four key aspects: beliefs in luck, rejection of luck, being lucky, and being unlucky. People who believe in good luck are more optimistic, more satisfied with their lives, and have better moods. People who believe they are personally unlucky experience more anxiety, and less likely to take advantage of unexpected opportunities.<sup><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luck#cite_note-popsci-10">[10]</a></sup>One 2010 study found that golfers who were told they were using a "lucky ball" performed better than those who were not.</p><p>Some people intentionally put themselves in situations that increase the chances of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serendipity">serendipitous</a> encounter, such as socializing with people who work in different fields.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Looking for Artistic Inspiration]]></title><description><![CDATA[Inspiration is an unconscious burst of creativity in a literary, musical, or other artistic endeavour. The Greeks believed that inspiration came from the muses]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/looking-for-artistic-inspiration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0650</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsty Bowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1563226659-69d3d7239a21-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1563226659-69d3d7239a21-1.jpg" alt="Looking for Artistic Inspiration"><p><strong>Inspiration</strong> is an unconscious burst of creativity in a literary, musical, or other artistic endeavour. The concept has origins in both Hellenism and Hebraism. The Greeks believed that inspiration or "enthusiasm" came from the muses, as well as the gods Apollo and Dionysus. Similarly, in the Ancient Norse religions, inspiration derives from the gods, such as Odin. Inspiration is also a divine matter in Hebrewpoetics. In the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Amos">Book of Amos</a> the prophet speaks of being overwhelmed by God's voice and compelled to speak. In Christianity, inspiration is a gift of the Holy Spirit.</p><p>In the 18th century philosopher <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Locke">John Locke</a> proposed a model of the human mind in which ideas associate or resonate with one another in the mind. In the 19th century, Romantic poets such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_Taylor_Coleridge">Coleridge</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Bysshe_Shelley">Shelley</a> believed that inspiration came to a poet because the poet was attuned to the (divine or mystical) "winds" and because the soul of the poet was able to receive such visions. In the early 20th century, Psychoanalyst <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud">Sigmund Freud</a> believed himself to have located inspiration in the inner psyche of the artist.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><blockquote>
<p>My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style.<br>
<cite>Maya Angelou</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>The Marxist theory of art sees it as the expression of the friction between economic base and economic superstructural positions, or as an unaware dialog of competing ideologies, or as an exploitation of a "fissure" in the ruling class's ideology. In modern psychology inspiration is not frequently studied, but it is generally seen as an entirely internal process.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562151404-9f198236130d-1.jpg" width="1290" height="764" alt="Looking for Artistic Inspiration"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1563226659-69d3d7239a21-2.jpg" width="1290" height="764" alt="Looking for Artistic Inspiration"></div></div><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562361233-cc2d6fcd95f5-1.jpg" width="1290" height="1177" alt="Looking for Artistic Inspiration"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1562361233-2c977823327f-1.jpg" width="1290" height="771" alt="Looking for Artistic Inspiration"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@vadimsadovski">Vadim Sadovski</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><h2 id="modernist-and-modern-concepts">Modernist and modern concepts</h2><p>In modern psychology, inspiration is not frequently studied, but it is generally seen as an entirely internal process. In each view, however, whether empiricist or mystical, inspiration is, by its nature, beyond control.</p><p>An example of a modern study on inspiration is one that was conducted by Takeshi Okada and Kentaro Ishibashi, published in 2016 in the multidisciplinary journal, <em>Cognitive Science. </em>In this three-part study, groups of Japanese undergraduate art students were observed to determine whether copying or simply musing upon example artworks that served as their inspiration would increase their creative output. </p><blockquote>Instead of trying to make your life perfect, give yourself the freedom to make it an adventure, and go ever upward.</blockquote><p>The results of the first and second experiment revealed that copying artwork enabled the students to produce creative drawings that were qualitatively different, but only when the example—the inspiration—featured a style that was unfamiliar to the students. The third experiment revealed that only musing upon the unfamiliar inspiration produced the same effect as copying it. Okada and Ishibashi suggest that these unfamiliar examples were able to facilitate the creativity of the students because they challenged the students' perspectives on drawing. They admit, however, that it is unclear whether their results can be generalized to professional artists as well, but they cite examples of artists, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Picasso">Pablo Picasso</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vincent_van_Gogh">Vincent van Gogh</a>, who extensively imitated the work of other artists, which might suggest that "imitation is an effective driver of creativity, even for experts."</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[I Have a Dream]]></title><description><![CDATA[I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/i-have-a-dream/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0657</guid><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Pollock]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1494249465471-5655b7878482.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1494249465471-5655b7878482.jpg" alt="I Have a Dream"><p>I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation.</p><p>Five score years ago, a great American, in whose symbolic shadow we stand today, signed the Emancipation Proclamation. This momentous decree came as a great beacon light of hope to millions of Negro slaves who had been seared in the flames of withering injustice. It came as a joyous daybreak to end the long night of their captivity.</p><p>But one hundred years later, the Negro still is not free. One hundred years later, the life of the Negro is still sadly crippled by the manacles of segregation and the chains of discrimination. One hundred years later, the Negro lives on a lonely island of poverty in the midst of a vast ocean of material prosperity. One hundred years later, the Negro is still languished in the corners of American society and finds himself an exile in his own land. And so we've come here today to dramatize a shameful condition.</p><p>In a sense we've come to our nation's capital to cash a check. When the architects of our republic wrote the magnificent words of the Constitution and the Declaration of Independence, they were signing a promissory note to which every American was to fall heir. This note was a promise that all men, yes, black men as well as white men, would be guaranteed the "unalienable Rights" of "Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness." It is obvious today that America has defaulted on this promissory note, insofar as her citizens of color are concerned. Instead of honoring this sacred obligation, America has given the Negro people a bad check, a check which has come back marked "insufficient funds."</p><blockquote>But we refuse to believe that the bank of justice is bankrupt. We refuse to believe that there are insufficient funds in the great vaults of opportunity of this nation.</blockquote><p>And so, we've come to cash this check, a check that will give us upon demand the riches of freedom and the security of justice.</p><p>We have also come to this hallowed spot to remind America of the fierce urgency of Now. This is no time to engage in the luxury of cooling off or to take the tranquilizing drug of gradualism. Now is the time to make real the promises of democracy. Now is the time to rise from the dark and desolate valley of segregation to the sunlit path of racial justice. Now is the time to lift our nation from the quicksands of racial injustice to the solid rock of brotherhood. Now is the time to make justice a reality for all of God's children.</p><p>It would be fatal for the nation to overlook the urgency of the moment. This sweltering summer of the Negro's legitimate discontent will not pass until there is an invigorating autumn of freedom and equality. Nineteen sixty-three is not an end, but a beginning. And those who hope that the Negro needed to blow off steam and will now be content will have a rude awakening if the nation returns to business as usual. And there will be neither rest nor tranquility in America until the Negro is granted his citizenship rights. The whirlwinds of revolt will continue to shake the foundations of our nation until the bright day of justice emerges.</p><p>But there is something that I must say to my people, who stand on the warm threshold which leads into the palace of justice: In the process of gaining our rightful place, we must not be guilty of wrongful deeds. Let us not seek to satisfy our thirst for freedom by drinking from the cup of bitterness and hatred. We must forever conduct our struggle on the high plane of dignity and discipline. We must not allow our creative protest to degenerate into physical violence. Again and again, we must rise to the majestic heights of meeting physical force with soul force.</p><p>The marvelous new militancy which has engulfed the Negro community must not lead us to a distrust of all white people, for many of our white brothers, as evidenced by their presence here today, have come to realize that their destiny is tied up with our destiny. And they have come to realize that their freedom is inextricably bound to our freedom.</p><p>We cannot walk alone.</p><p>And as we walk, we must make the pledge that we shall always march ahead.</p><p>We cannot turn back.</p><p>There are those who are asking the devotees of civil rights, "When will you be satisfied?" We can never be satisfied as long as the Negro is the victim of the unspeakable horrors of police brutality. We can never be satisfied as long as our bodies, heavy with the fatigue of travel, cannot gain lodging in the motels of the highways and the hotels of the cities. We cannot be satisfied as long as the negro's basic mobility is from a smaller ghetto to a larger one. We can never be satisfied as long as our children are stripped of their self-hood and robbed of their dignity by signs stating: "For Whites Only." We cannot be satisfied as long as a Negro in Mississippi cannot vote and a Negro in New York believes he has nothing for which to vote. No, no, we are not satisfied, and we will not be satisfied until "justice rolls down like waters, and righteousness like a mighty stream."</p><p>I am not unmindful that some of you have come here out of great trials and tribulations. Some of you have come fresh from narrow jail cells. And some of you have come from areas where your quest -- quest for freedom left you battered by the storms of persecution and staggered by the winds of police brutality. You have been the veterans of creative suffering. Continue to work with the faith that unearned suffering is redemptive. Go back to Mississippi, go back to Alabama, go back to South Carolina, go back to Georgia, go back to Louisiana, go back to the slums and ghettos of our northern cities, knowing that somehow this situation can and will be changed.</p><p>Let us not wallow in the valley of despair, I say to you today, my friends.</p><blockquote>And so even though we face the difficulties of today and tomorrow, I still have a dream. It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream.</blockquote><p>I have a dream that one day this nation will rise up and live out the true meaning of its creed: "We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal."</p><p>I have a dream that one day on the red hills of Georgia, the sons of former slaves and the sons of former slave owners will be able to sit down together at the table of brotherhood.</p><p>I have a dream that one day even the state of Mississippi, a state sweltering with the heat of injustice, sweltering with the heat of oppression, will be transformed into an oasis of freedom and justice.</p><p>I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.</p><p>I have a <strong><strong>dream</strong></strong> today!</p><p>I have a dream that one day, down in Alabama, with its vicious racists, with its governor having his lips dripping with the words of "interposition" and "nullification" -- one day right there in Alabama little black boys and black girls will be able to join hands with little white boys and white girls as sisters and brothers.</p><p>I have a <strong><strong>dream</strong></strong> today!</p><p>I have a dream that one day every valley shall be exalted, and every hill and mountain shall be made low, the rough places will be made plain, and the crooked places will be made straight; "and the glory of the Lord shall be revealed and all flesh shall see it together."</p><p>This is our hope, and this is the faith that I go back to the South with.</p><p>With this faith, we will be able to hew out of the mountain of despair a stone of hope. With this faith, we will be able to transform the jangling discords of our nation into a beautiful symphony of brotherhood. With this faith, we will be able to work together, to pray together, to struggle together, to go to jail together, to stand up for freedom together, knowing that we will be free one day.</p><p>And this will be the day -- this will be the day when all of God's children will be able to sing with new meaning:</p><p><em><em>My country 'tis of thee, sweet land of liberty, of thee I sing.</em></em><br><em><em>Land where my fathers died, land of the Pilgrim's pride,</em></em><br><em><em>From every mountainside, let freedom ring!</em></em></p><p>And if America is to be a great nation, this must become true.</p><p>And so let freedom ring from the prodigious hilltops of New Hampshire.</p><p><em><em>Let freedom ring from the mighty mountains of New York.</em></em><br><em><em>Let freedom ring from the heightening Alleghenies of Pennsylvania.</em></em><br><em><em>Let freedom ring from the snow-capped Rockies of Colorado.</em></em><br><em><em>Let freedom ring from the curvaceous slopes of California.</em></em></p><p>But not only that:</p><p><em><em>Let freedom ring from Stone Mountain of Georgia.</em></em><br><em><em>Let freedom ring from Lookout Mountain of Tennessee.</em></em><br><em><em>Let freedom ring from every hill and molehill of Mississippi.</em></em><br><em><em>From every mountainside, let freedom ring.</em></em></p><p>And when this happens, and when we allow freedom ring, when we let it ring from every village and every hamlet, from every state and every city, we will be able to speed up that day when all of God's children, black men and white men, Jews and Gentiles, Protestants and Catholics, will be able to join hands and sing in the words of the old Negro spiritual:</p><p><em><em>Free at last! Free at last!</em></em></p><p><em><em>Thank God Almighty, we are free at last!</em></em></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Next generation theme]]></title><description><![CDATA[I had this story from one who had no business to tell it to me, or to any other. I may credit the seductive influence of an old vintage upon the narrator]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/next-generation-theme/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0652</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Pollock]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1543868519-0e147b44e366-2.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1543868519-0e147b44e366-2.jpg" alt="Next generation theme"><p>I had this story from one who had no business to tell it to me, or to any other. I may credit the seductive influence of an old vintage upon the narrator for the beginning of it, and my own skeptical incredulity during the days that followed for the balance of the strange tale.</p><p>When my convivial host discovered that he had told me so much, and that I was prone to doubtfulness, his foolish pride assumed the task the old vintage had commenced, and so he unearthed written evidence in the form of musty manuscript, and dry official records of the British Colonial Office to support many of the salient features of his remarkable narrative.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><blockquote>
<p>I strive for two things in design: simplicity and clarity. Great design is born of those two things.<br>
<cite>Lindon Leader</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>I do not say the story is true, for I did not witness the happenings which it portrays, but the fact that in the telling of it to you I have taken fictitious names for the principal characters quite sufficiently evidences the sincerity of my own belief that it MAY be true.</p><p>The yellow, mildewed pages of the diary of a man long dead, and the records of the Colonial Office dovetail perfectly with the narrative of my convivial host, and so I give you the story as I painstakingly pieced it out from these several various agencies.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1543868519-6547a0f61a21.jpg" width="680" height="850" alt="Next generation theme"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1543868519-fc5437bc63fe.jpg" width="1290" height="860" alt="Next generation theme"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@kbalobanov">Kirill Balobanov</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><p>If you do not find it credible you will at least be as one with me in acknowledging that it is unique, remarkable, and interesting. From the records of the Colonial Office and from the dead man's diary we learn that a certain young English nobleman, whom we shall call John Clayton, Lord Greystoke, was commissioned to make a peculiarly delicate investigation of conditions in a British West Coast African Colony from whose simple native inhabitants another European power was known to be recruiting soldiers for its native army, which it used solely for the forcible collection of rubber and ivory from the savage tribes along the Congo and the Aruwimi. The natives of the British Colony complained that many of their young men were enticed away through the medium of fair and glowing promises, but that few if any ever returned to their families.</p><p>The Englishmen in Africa went even further, saying that these poor blacks were held in virtual slavery, since after their terms of enlistment expired their ignorance was imposed upon by their white officers, and they were told that they had yet several years to serve.</p><p>And so the Colonial Office appointed John Clayton to a new post in British West Africa, but his confidential instructions centered on a thorough investigation of the unfair treatment of black British subjects by the officers of a friendly European power. Why he was sent, is, however, of little moment to this story, for he never made an investigation, nor, in fact, did he ever reach his destination.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/kirill-balobanov-CAB6-rZhAxw-unsplash.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Next generation theme"></figure><p>Clayton was the type of Englishman that one likes best to associate with the noblest monuments of historic achievement upon a thousand victorious battlefields--a strong, virile man --mentally, morally, and physically.</p><p>In stature he was above the average height; his eyes were gray, his features regular and strong; his carriage that of perfect, robust health influenced by his years of army training.</p><p>Political ambition had caused him to seek transference from the army to the Colonial Office and so we find him, still young, entrusted with a delicate and important commission in the service of the Queen.</p><p>When he received this appointment he was both elated and appalled. The preferment seemed to him in the nature of a well-merited reward for painstaking and intelligent service, and as a stepping stone to posts of greater importance and responsibility; but, on the other hand, he had been married to the Hon. Alice Rutherford for scarce a three months, and it was the thought of taking this fair young girl into the dangers and isolation of tropical Africa that appalled him.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Purpose of Education]]></title><description><![CDATA[As I engage in the so-called "bull sessions" around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education]]></description><link>https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/the-purpose-of-education/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6083000a9f9d971e98ad0656</guid><category><![CDATA[Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[Story]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Pollock]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 07:39:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1566242635312-e58f0e7fb83a.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1566242635312-e58f0e7fb83a.jpg" alt="The Purpose of Education"><p>As I engage in the so-called "bull sessions" around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the "brethren" think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.</p><blockquote>It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture.</blockquote><p>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking. To think incisively and to think for one's self is very difficult. We are prone to let our mental life become invaded by legions of half truths, prejudices, and propaganda. At this point, I often wonder whether or not education is fulfilling its purpose. A great majority of the so-called educated people do not think logically and scientifically. Even the press, the classroom, the platform, and the pulpit in many instances do not give us objective and unbiased truths. To save man from the morass of propaganda, in my opinion, is one of the chief aims of education. Education must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide kg-card-hascaption"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1556986124-8fb780a67cdc.jpg" width="680" height="907" alt="The Purpose of Education"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1519627745017-8f1c7ec8d37d.jpg" width="680" height="1061" alt="The Purpose of Education"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://demo.visual-themes.com/noord/content/images/2019/09/photo-1525226821587-9412a5c8e7e6.jpg" width="680" height="907" alt="The Purpose of Education"></div></div></div><figcaption>Photos by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@seemoris">Caleb George</a> / <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure><p>The function of education, therefore, is to teach one to think intensively and to think critically. But education which stops with efficiency may prove the greatest menace to society. The most dangerous criminal may be the man gifted with reason, but with no morals.</p><p>The late Eugene Talmadge, in my opinion, possessed one of the better minds of Georgia, or even America. Moreover, he wore the Phi Beta Kappa key. By all measuring rods, Mr. Talmadge could think critically and intensively; yet he contends that I am an inferior being. Are those the types of men we call educated?</p><p>We must remember that intelligence is not enough. Intelligence plus character--that is the goal of true education. The complete education gives one not only power of concentration, but worthy objectives upon which to concentrate. The broad education will, therefore, transmit to one not only the accumulated knowledge of the race but also the accumulated experience of social living.</p><p>If we are not careful, our colleges will produce a group of close-minded, unscientific, illogical propagandists, consumed with immoral acts. Be careful, "brethren!" Be careful, teachers!</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>